親方！
Boss!
ダメダメ！　ストーップ！
No, no!
Stop!
あ？
Huh?
どうしたい？
これからってときに。
What's wrong?
I was just about to start!
えらいこっちゃ！
This is terrible!
ダンゾウ様が
亡くなっちまったそうです。
It seems Lord Danzo has died!
６代目火影はなしだ　なし！
He's not the Sixth Hokage anymore!
Not anymore!
な　なんだと！
What are you saying?
こちとら
ダンゾウ様の顔が夢に浮かぶほど→
I've prepared and I've studied
Lord Danzo's face so well
下準備してきたってのに！
I even see him in my dreams!
チッ！　べらんめぇ
ちくしょうめ！
Damn… What the heck?!
で　次の火影になるのは→
So… Who's going to be
the next Hokage?
いったい誰なんでい？
（カカシ）もともとは
大蛇丸の部下だったのが→
INTEL DIVISION
She originally worked
for Orochimaru
サスケの仲間になり
暁として動いていた忍です。
before she joined up with Sasuke
as a shinobi for the Akatsuki.
（イビキ）いろいろと知っている
ということだな。
That means she knows a lot.
（香燐）大事に扱えよ。
You better treat me well.
それと
サスケとダンゾウとの戦いの場に→
And…
It looks like she was there when
Sasuke and Danzo battled it out.
居合わせていたようです。
２人の戦いを見ていたのか？
You saw them fighting?
こんなところで　もう尋問かよ。
You're interrogating me here?
よし　コイツは
情報部で身柄を預かる。
Okay, we'll hold her at
the Intel Division.
知っていることは
みな聞き出そう。
We'll get everything she knows.
連れていけ。
はい。
Take her away.
Yes, sir.
あっ　ちょっと　やだ！
Hey…no! I won't try to escape.
逃げたりしないから。
So let go of me, will you?!
その手　放せよ！
ったく！
Jeez!
のどもカラカラだから
何か飲み物ちょうだい。
I'm so thirsty,
give me something to drink!
ところで　綱手様の容態は？
By the way,
how's Lady Tsunade doing?
相変わらず意識不明だ。
She's still unconscious.
そうか。
I see.
じゃ　俺は上へ報告に行くから
これで…。
Well, I'll go make my report
to the superiors.
Excuse me.
カカシ。
Kakashi…
木ノ葉隠れの里は今→
The chain of command in
the Hidden Leaf Village
命令系統がズタズタだ。
is in shambles.
一刻も早く
誰かが立て直さねばならん。
Someone has to restore order
as soon as possible.
ああ　わかっているつもりだ。
Yeah… I know that.
Kakashi Hatake, the Hokage
Sasuke did that?
（シカマル）サスケが　そんなことを。
（シノ）ああ　信じられない事態だな。
It's an unbelievable situation.
（赤丸）クゥーン…。
That's why I want you to
let me handle Sasuke.
（ナルト）だから　サスケのことは
俺に任せてほしいんだ。
You'll take on Sasuke alone?!
（テンテン）サスケをひとりでやる？
How can you expect us
to agree to that?
そんなんで　私たちみんなが
納得できるわけないでしょ。
テンテンの言うとおりだ　ナルト。
Tenten is right, Naruto.
We can't just give in to
your stubbornness.
お前ひとりのわがままには
つきあっていられない。
The reason is because
this is a big problem for the village.
なぜなら
これは里の大きな問題だ。
I'm not being stubborn.
これは　わがままじゃねえんだ。
You said you'd give us
the details when we got home,
（キバ）帰ってから詳しく話す
っつうからよ→
but I never thought
this is what you'd say!
何を言うかと思えば！
We've all made up our minds
to kill Sasuke!
俺たちだって覚悟して→
サスケのことを殺すって
決めたんだぞ！
おい　ナルト　お前　まさか→
Hey Naruto, don't tell me
you're saying
you'll get Sasuke all by yourself,
１人でやるって
言っておきながら→
when you're actually planning
to protect him.
サスケをかばうってんじゃ
ねえだろうな。
ああ　サスケをかばうなんて
そんなつもりはねえよ。
No, I have no intention
of protecting Sasuke.
– Chidori!
– Rasengan!
((サスケ：千鳥！
螺旋丸！))
（ネジ）五影会談で
大立ち回りをやらかし→
After all that fighting at
the Five Kage Summit,
その後　ダンゾウと戦って
そこまで弱っていたサスケなら→
and fighting Danzo…
If Sasuke was weakened
at that time,
なんで
一気に片をつけなかった？
why didn't you take
him out right then?
（サクラ）マダラもいたし　そんなに
簡単な感じじゃなかった。
Madara was there too!
It didn't seem so easy.
それに…。
Besides…
That's no reason to let him
get away so easily!
だからってよ
みすみす逃がすことはねえだろ。
Hey Naruto…
おい　ナルト　オメエは強いんだぜ。
You're strong.
You're the hero who
took down Pain, aren't you?!
ペインぶっ倒した
英雄ってやつだろうが。
Hero?
英雄？
ああ。
Yeah. You could take Sasuke down
like you did back then.
サスケの野郎も
あんときみてえによ。
That's not true.
そうじゃねえんだ。
あ？
Huh?
そんなんで
今のサスケは倒せねえ。
I wouldn't be able to beat Sasuke
with something like that now.
That's what I found out.
それが　わかった。
Inside him…
《アイツの中にも…》
（チョウジ）
わかったって　いったい何が？
What is it that you found out?
In any case, nobody should take
on Sasuke as he is now.
とにかく　今のサスケとは
誰も戦っちゃダメだ。
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ？
I'm the only one who can fight him.
戦えるのは俺しかいねえ
そういう意味だ。
That's what I mean.
そんなんじゃ
何にも　わかんないわよ。
That doesn't tell us anything!
Explain it in detail.
What happened?
詳しく説明しろ
何があったんだ？
I said I'd tell you when
the time comes.
言うべきときが来たら
言うってばよ。
Hey! There you go again!
Giving us the runaround!
あっ　おい！
また　はぐらかす気かよ　テメエ。
Damn it.
ったく！
《ナルト？》
Naruto…
((サスケ。
Sasuke…
お前も本当の心の内が
読めたのかよ。
Were you able to read…
この俺のよ。
what was inside of my heart?
それに見えただろ？
And you saw it, didn't you?
お前と俺が戦えば→
That if you and I fight…
(２人とも死ぬ))
we will both die.
《いったい　何を隠しているの？》
What are you hiding?
じゃ　そういうことで
よろしくだってばよ。
Well…
Please leave it to me.
あっ　おい　こら　ナルト！
Hey! Naruto!
Naruto…
ナルト。
おい　ナルト！
Hey, Naruto!
（コハル）ダンゾウまでものう。
Danzo too?
（ホムラ）まったく　優秀なヤツほど
先にいきおる。
Such a shame.
The best ones go first.
これから　すぐにでも→
We must quickly hold a meeting
to determine who will
be the next Hokage.
火影を決める会議を
開かなくてはな。
忍連合についても
火影不在では事が進まん。
The Allied Shinobi Force
will be stalled
if the Hokage is missing.
That cannot be helped.
こうなっては　しかたがない。
We will recommend you for Hokage.
私らは　お前を火影に推す。
The Sand,
a member of the alliance,
同盟の砂からも
お前にと推薦があった。
has also recommended you.
覚悟はできてます。
I am prepared for it.
ほう　やけに素直だな。
Oh… That was easy.
Of course, it would be a little
out of character for me
まあ　火影なんて
俺の柄じゃないんですけどね。
to be the Hokage.
That's fine.
まあ　よい。　大名様たちに
会議の要請をしてくる。
I will go to the Feudal Lords
to request a conference.
Go back to the village and
prepare until you are called.
呼び出されるまで
里で準備をしておけ。
特に準備ってほどのものも
ありませんがね。
There really isn't anything
for me to prepare.
カカシよ　次の火影のお前に
これだけは言っておく。
Listen, Kakashi.
Let me just say one thing
to the next Hokage.
ダンゾウは
確かに野心家ではあったが→
It is true that Danzo
was very ambitious,
すべては里のためだった。
but everything he did was
for the sake of the village.
表にヒルゼン　裏にダンゾウ。
Hiruzen out front and
Danzo in the back.
あの頃の木ノ葉が
いちばんうまくいっていた。
Things went most smoothly
in Hidden Leaf back then.
それは　何かの言い訳ですか？
Is that meant to be
some sort of excuse?
忠告だ。
Just some advice.
１人で　すべてを抱え込むな。
Don't try to take on everything
by yourself.
傍らに誰か腹心がいるのが
理想だ。
It would be best to have
a confidant beside you.
あの頃の仲間も
わしらだけになったか。
We are the only ones remaining
from the old days.
忍のさだめは
わからぬものよのう。
There is no telling what
the fate of the shinobi will be.
《先生　この俺が
火影だそうですよ》
Sensei… They say I am going
to be the next Hokage.
（ガイ）よう　カカシ！
Yo! Kakashi!
無事に戻ってきたようだな！
Looks like you got home safely.
体の調子はどうだ？
How are you?
おい　ケガなんか
してないだろうな？
You weren't injured, were you?
ああ　大丈夫だけど。
Oh, I'm fine.
よ～し！　では　久しぶりに
勝負といこうじゃないか！
Okay, in that case…
It's been a while,
so why don't we have a match?
なんで？
Why?
なんでって　何を今さら！
Why?!
Why? What do you mean?
それは　俺とお前が
永遠のライバルだからではないか！
Because you and I
are eternal rivals, that's why!
これまでの百を超える戦いに
今　新たな一戦を加えるだけだ！
We've had over
100 matches up till now.
Let's add another one!
んじゃ…。
おい　写輪眼はなしだぞ。
In that case…
No using the Sharingan now.
（２人）ジャンケン　ジャンケン…。
– Rock, paper, scissors!
ノ～ッ！　ジャンケンは
ジャンケンだけは　絶対　認めんぞ！
No!
Not that! I don't want
Rock Paper Scissors!
勝負は　見よ　あれだ！
Our challenge will be…that!
あの上に　ゴールを設営してある。
I've set up a goal up there.
あそこまで競争だ！　いいか！？
We'll race to there.
今　それどころじゃ…。
This is not the time for…
That's exactly why
I want to have a hot challenge.
だから　この時だからこそ→
俺は　お前と
熱い勝負がしたいんだ　カカシ！
受けてくれるな？
我が永遠のライバルよ！
You'll accept it, won't you,
my eternal rival?!
フッ　そうだな
今しかないか…。
You're right.
No time like the present I guess.
よ～し　勝負だ！
All right! Let's do it!
え～っ！？　スタートも　わざわざ
里の入り口からやるの？
What? You want to start way out
at the entrance to the village?
おお　そうよ！
I want to enjoy this challenge
to the fullest.
この勝負　じっくり
楽しみたいからな！
さあ　準備はいいか？
はい　いつでも。
Are you ready?
Anytime…
（２人）スタート！
– Start!
♪～
うわ～っ！
なはは～！
ぐわっ…　イテエ！
Ouch…
いつの間に　そんなものを！？
When did you get those things?!
いや　スタート前に
がれきの中からな。
Oh, before we started.
From a pile of rubble.
くう　卑怯な！　そら！！
That's not fair.
Take that!
あっ　ホイ！
なんの！
What?
Take that!
Ouch!
ナルトのこと考えてるの？
Are you thinking about Naruto?
うん？　まあな。
Yeah…
やめときなよ　ムダだと思うよ。
ムダ？
Forget it. I don't think
it'll do any good.
Won't do any good?
ナルトが　しゃべらないなら
何もわからないでしょ。
If Naruto doesn't talk,
we won't find out anything.
Here.
ほら。
フッ　だな。
I guess.
なんだ　ありゃ？
何かあったのかな？
What was that?
Has something happened?
うお～！
ハハハ！　復興中の里の道は
いつもと違って先が読めん。
With the village being reconstructed,
the roads are all different and
I can't tell where we're going!
ハハ！
そのようだな。
Seems like it!
うん？
What is that?
ねえ　あれじゃ　みんな
納得してないと思うんだけど。
Listen, I don't think
anyone will be satisfied
with the way things stand.
何が？
サスケ君のことよ。
What are you talking about?
About Sasuke…
サクラちゃんは
納得してんのか？
Are you satisfied, Sakura?
私は　ナルトに
何か考えがあるようだから→
I think you have
some sort of plan, so…
信じることにした。
I'm putting my faith in you!
カカシ先生と　ガイ先生？
Is that Kakashi Sensei
and Guy Sensei?!
速ぇ～！
So fast!
あの２人
まさか　またあれか？
Those two… Don't tell me
they're at it again?!
間違いないわよ
２人のライバル勝負。
No mistake about it.
It's their rivalry contest.
きっとまた　ガイ先生が
ふっかけたんだわ。
Guy Sensei probably challenged him.
まったく　こんなときに。
Of all the times to do this.
いや　こんなときだからこそ
もちかけたんだろうな。
No, that's exactly why
he challenged him now.
えっ　なんで？
Huh?! Why?
さすが　我がライバル　カカシよ！
As expected from my rival!
さあ　勝負は　ここからだ！
おう！
The challenge has just begun!
Yeah!
（２人）とう！
ガイ先生が勝負をしている間
僕も共に戦います！
While Guy Sensei is battling it out,
I will fight too!
せや～！
リ－　どっちが勝った？
Lee, who won?
（リー）カカシ先生の勝ちです！
Kakashi Sensei is…
the winner!
なかなか
いい勝負だったじゃないか。
That was a pretty good challenge.
ん？
おめでとう。
Congratulations!
いや…
こんな勝負に勝ったくらいで。
Oh no… This is nothing
to be congratulated for.
火影就任　おめでとう！
Congratulations on becoming
the next Hokage!
火影ともなれば
気軽に俺との勝負にのることも→
When you become the Hokage,
you probably won't be able to
accept my challenges so easily.
無理だろうからな。
That's why I wanted to
challenge you for the last time
だから　その前に　お前との
最後の勝負がしたかったんだ。
before it happened.
ありがとう　カカシ！
Thank you, Kakashi.
これが
最後ってわけじゃないさ。
This isn't the last time.
俺とお前が
永遠のライバルには変わりない。
We'll still be eternal rivals.
That won't change.
えっ！
Huh?!
Guy, seriously,
I find it reassuring having you there.
ガイ…　真面目な話
お前がいてくれて　俺は心強いよ。
これからも　よろしくな。
I hope I can count on
your continued support.
うぅ…　カ　カカシ…。
Ka-Kakashi…
俺一人で　この里を
まとめあげることは…。
I can't bring this whole village
– together by myself.
– You're making me cry.
おい！　聞いてんのか！
おい！　おい！
– Hey are you listening? Hey! Hey!
– I'm listening.
あぁ～っ！
You're Kakashi Hatake, aren't you?
The next Hokage?
アンタ　はたけカカシさんだろ？
次の火影の…。
Yes, well…
はぁ　まあ。
Oh, this is perfect!
Let me measure your face!
いやぁ　ちょうどよかった。
顔　測らせてくれ！
型もとりてぇな。
な　なんですか？
I want to get a mold too.
W-What is this?
顔岩だよ　顔岩！　火影の！
It's for the Great Stone Faces.
The Stone Faces of the Hokage!
今から
ちょっと　つきあってもらうぜ！
I need you to come with me.
あぁ　ちょ　ちょっと！
J-Just a minute.
火影ともなると
うん。
大変みたいですね。
It seems it's not easy
being the Hokage.
我が永遠のライバルに
一歩　先へ行かれてしまったか。
I guess I've been one-upped
by my eternal rival.
だが！
はい！
However…
Yes! Now it is your turn to pass him.
次は　ガイ先生が抜き返す番です。
カカシが　火影になるのなら
俺は　その先を目指す！
If Kakashi is to become the Hokage,
I will aim beyond that!
火影の先まで
いってみせるぞ！
I will go beyond Hokage,
far and beyond!
あの　はるかなる彼方まで！
頑張ってください！　ガイ先生！
おうよ！
Good luck, Sensei!
Thanks!
By the way,
what is beyond the Hokage?
ところで　火影の先には
何があるんですか？
なんだろうな…。
I wonder what it is.
♪～
髪型は　これでいいんだな？
This hairstyle is okay, right?
あの…。
額当ては斜めね。
Umm…
The headband should be
at an angle.
適当でいいんですけど。
You don't have to be exact.
冗談　言うない！
You must be joking.
Once it's carved,
it can't be changed easily.
一度　彫ったら
簡単には変更できねえんだ！
はぁ…。
これで　よし！
I see.
That's it! We haven't
missed anything, have we?
もれはねえな！
へい　親方！
No, sir!
じゃあ次は
型とりの準備といこう。
Then let's get ready to
make the mold.
ほい　きた！
Got it!
えっ！？　石膏ですか？
おうよ！
Is that plaster?
That's right.
つまり　こいつを
薄く　顔に塗り重ねて→
We'll paint this on you
in thin layers
型をとるって寸法よ！
to make a mold of your face!
早速　いきてぇんだが
それ　とってくんねえかな？
I want to start right away,
but you'll have to take that off.
えっ！？
そのマスクだよ！
What?!
That mask.
顔岩なのに　顔を隠してちゃ
シャレになんねえや！
Your Stone Face won't look good
if you're hiding your face.
（シズネ）誰か　誰か早く！
Somebody! Somebody,
come quickly! Please!
どうなされた！？
What's happened?
シズネ　まさか…。
Shizune… Don't tell me…
（シカク）受けてくれて助かる。
Thanks for accepting.
シカクさんが火影になってくれれば
俺も助かるんですが。
I would feel a lot better
if you would become
the Hokage, Shikaku.
バカを言え。
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm old enough to retire and
have my son take over.
俺は息子にあとを任せて
隠居しても　おかしくないんだぞ。
もっとも
そうも言ってられないがな。
Of course,
I'm in no position to do that.
はい。
Yes.
あのダンゾウが
暁との戦いで散ったとな。
To think that Danzo fell
to the Akatsuki.
はい。
また　火影を決めねばならんな。
Yes.
We must decide on another Hokage.
我ら一同
はたけカカシを推薦します。
We are all recommending
Kakashi Hatake.
ほぉ～　あの者か。
Oh, that man?
はたけカカシ　入れ。
Kakashi Hatake, enter.
ほぉ～　ええじゃないかえ。
Oh… Seems like a good choice.
よし　では　はたけカカシ　お前を…。
All right. Now then, Kakashi Hatake,
I appoint you…
お前を…　う～ん。
大名様　いかがなされた？
My lord, what is wrong?
いやな　第何代の火影と
任命したらよいかのう。
Oh, well… What number Hokage
do I appoint him?
何代とは？
What number?
ダンゾウを６代目としたが
正式就任前に死によった。
Danzo was appointed Number Six,
but he died before
he formally assumed the office.
カカシを６代としたらよいのやら
７代にしたらよいのやら。
I don't know if Kakashi should
be Number Six or Number Seven.
たとえ正式就任前とはいえ
ダンゾウは…。
Even if Danzo had not
formally assumed the office…
欠番？
やはり６代で。
A missing number?
He should be Number Six.
いや　７代だろう。
No, I think Number Seven.
But Number Six never really…
しかし　６代は実際には…。
うむ　うむうむ。
あい　わかった
はたけカカシ　お前を…。
All right. Kakashi Hatake!
You will be…
失礼します！
ガイ！
Please excuse me!
Guy?
何事ぞ
大事な会議の最中であるぞ。
What is this?!
We are in an important conference.
事態の急変を伝えにまいりました。
I have come to report a sudden change
in the state of affairs!
なに！？　急変だと？
What? A sudden change?!
綱手様！
Lady Tsunade!
（綱手）シズネ　痛い。
Shizune…you're hurting me.
他の里に伝令を出せ。
Send messages to
the other villages!
木ノ葉の火影　綱手は健在だとな。
Tsunade, the Hokage
of Hidden Leaf Village,
is alive and well!
他国の大名たちにも
このことを伝えよ。
Report this to the Feudal Lords
of the other lands as well.
里の者たちにも
早く伝えたほうがいいでしょう。
We should let the people of
our village know at once.
そちらは　お前に任せる。
I will leave that to you.
あの…。
Umm… Well…
俺　帰ってもいいっすか？
May I go home?
せっかく　ここまで来たんだ。
回転寿司でも食って行こうぜ。
Since we're here now,
why don't we go and eat at
that sushi boat restaurant?
何皿食えるか勝負だ。
Let's see who can eat the most!
親方　ダメダメ　ストップ！
Boss!
It's no good! Stop!
あ？　どうした？
What happened?
綱手様が
火影に復帰したそうです。
They say Lady Tsunade has
been reinstated as the Hokage.
べらんめえ　また無駄骨か！
You gotta be kidding me!
I wasted my time again!
It was indeed I who summoned you.
Who're you again?
C'mon, could you remember
my name already?
＜　ちょっと変わった健康法が
日本全国から大集合＞